<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home page has underscore - _index.md on Tigrida Wealth</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home page has underscore - _index.md on Tigrida Wealth</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 14:44:21 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Are You On Track for Retirement?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/retirement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 14:44:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/retirement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-assess-your-pension-health&#34;&gt;How to Assess Your Pension Health&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To assess your pension health, start by answering:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How much do I need to retire comfortably?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How much have I already saved—and where is it invested?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Am I making full use of allowances (e.g. £60,000 annual pension contribution limit)?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use tools like pension calculators or seek regulated advice to create a clear retirement roadmap. Review regularly—especially after major life events or policy changes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drawdown vs Annuity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/drawdown-vs-annuity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 14:44:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/drawdown-vs-annuity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;choosing-the-right-retirement-income-strategy&#34;&gt;Choosing the Right Retirement Income Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When it’s time to start drawing your pension, you typically choose between:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Drawdown: Keeping your pension invested and drawing income as needed. Offers flexibility but comes with investment risk.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Annuity: A guaranteed income for life (or a set period). Offers security but less flexibility.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many retirees choose a blend of both. The right approach depends on your health, lifestyle needs, and risk tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generational Wealth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/generational-wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 14:44:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/generational-wealth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-prepare-your-family-for-inheritance&#34;&gt;How to Prepare Your Family for Inheritance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Transferring wealth isn’t just a legal process—it’s a family journey. To ensure your legacy endures:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start the conversation early with your children or beneficiaries.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Educate the next generation on financial responsibility.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use trusts to protect assets and control how and when they’re distributed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Document your intentions through wills and letters of wishes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Involve professionals (solicitors, tax advisers, wealth managers) to ensure everything is coordinated.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, good planning reduces friction and helps preserve not only wealth, but family harmony.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Align Your Investments With Your Values</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/alligning-investments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 14:44:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/alligning-investments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ethical or ESG investing allows you to support causes that matter—climate change, human rights, or corporate responsibility—without sacrificing financial goals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Define your values: What matters most to you?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Understand the spectrum: ESG integration, exclusions, impact investing, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Check fund transparency: Does the fund provider report on outcomes?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Balance principles with performance: Ethical investing should still meet your risk-return needs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Working with a firm that offers sustainable investment options can help you make informed, balanced choices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IHT Planning in 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/iht-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 14:44:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/iht-planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-stay-ahead-of-changes-in-uk-inheritance-tax-rules&#34;&gt;How to Stay Ahead of Changes in UK Inheritance Tax Rules&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inheritance Tax (IHT) remains a concern for many families—especially with thresholds frozen and asset values rising. Key steps include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Using your annual gifting allowance (£3,000 per person per year).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Passing on your main residence with the residence nil rate band (£175,000 per person).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Creating trusts or family investment companies, where appropriate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reviewing wills and nominations regularly.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Consult a regulated adviser to ensure your plan reflects current legislation and future changes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structuring Your Wealth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/structuring-your-wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 14:44:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/structuring-your-wealth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-uk-investors-guide&#34;&gt;A UK Investor’s Guide&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Structuring your wealth for longevity means balancing growth, preservation, and accessibility. In the UK context, consider:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Diversification across asset classes (equities, bonds, property, cash).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tax wrappers: ISAs, pensions (SIPP or workplace), and offshore bonds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Legal structures: Trusts, companies, or family investment companies where appropriate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Risk management: Insurance, liquidity buffers, and regular rebalancing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Legacy planning: Including lifetime gifting and wills.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Long-term success stems from aligning your portfolio with your evolving life goals—not just short-term market moves.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Asset Allocation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/asset-allocation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 14:44:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/asset-allocation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;for-resilient-investment-portfolio&#34;&gt;For Resilient Investment Portfolio&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Asset allocation—how your money is split between different asset classes—is the single biggest driver of portfolio performance. A resilient allocation:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spreads risk across equities, bonds, alternatives, and cash.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Matches your risk profile (e.g. cautious, balanced, adventurous).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Adapts over time—as you approach retirement, for example, you may reduce exposure to volatility.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Regularly reviewing your allocation helps keep your investments aligned with your life stage and goals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Risk vs Return</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/risk-vs-return/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 14:44:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/risk-vs-return/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-every-investor-should-know&#34;&gt;What Every Investor Should Know&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every investment decision involves a trade-off: higher potential returns usually come with higher risks. Understanding this relationship helps you:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Avoid overreaction during market dips.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Set realistic expectations for performance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Align your portfolio with your time horizon and financial goals.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Risk doesn’t just mean volatility—it includes inflation risk, liquidity risk, and behavioural risk. Diversifying and staying disciplined are key to managing these risks over time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wealth Management Plan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/wealth-management-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 14:44:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/wealth-management-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-does-a-good-wealth-management-plan-look-like&#34;&gt;What Does a Good Wealth Management Plan Look Like?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A good wealth management plan is more than just picking investments—it’s a holistic strategy tailored to your life goals, values, and financial situation. At its core, an effective plan should include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Clear objectives: Define what you want to achieve (retirement, a property purchase, business succession, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cash flow forecasting: Understanding how money moves in and out of your accounts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Investment strategy: Based on your risk appetite and time horizon.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tax efficiency: Making the most of your allowances, such as ISAs, pensions, and capital gains reliefs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Estate planning: Ensuring your wealth is passed on efficiently and according to your wishes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Regular reviews: Adapting your plan as life changes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Wealth Management Isn’t Just for the Ultra-Rich</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/not-for-the-rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 14:44:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/not-for-the-rich/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wealth management is often misunderstood as a service only for millionaires. In reality, it benefits anyone who:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Has multiple financial goals (e.g. retirement, kids’ education, business exit).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Needs tax-efficient planning.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wants peace of mind knowing a professional is managing the big picture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Faces complex decisions like pension consolidation or inheritance planning.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whether you have £100,000 or £10 million, smart planning can help protect and grow what you’ve worked hard to earn.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
